

# Shubham Mehta

Email: i.mehta.shubham@gmail.com Phone: (+49) 15510610158

Website: https://cutt.ly/Shubham\_portfolio

in LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/shubham-mehta1

Date of birth: 17 May 2001 Nationality: Indian

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a motivated and dedicated Mechanical Engineer, who graduated from Dwarkadas J. Sanghvi College of Engineering in Mumbai, India, with a strong interest in Robotics and Drones. I have completed technical, teaching, and management internships, providing valuable experience and knowledge. My ability to solve problems effectively, think creatively, have a work ethic, lead teams, communicate clearly, and manage time efficiently has made me a highly valuable member of any team.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# [ 11 Mar 2024 – 12 Aug 2024 ] **Technical operations lead**

Encora Air Pvt. Ltd

City: Mumbai | Country: India

- 1. **Lead** daily operations of the **technical department**.
- 2. **Plan** and **coordinate** technical processes with **cross-functional teams**.
- 3. **Ensure** compliance with industry **regulations** and **safety** standards.
- 4. Manage troubleshooting and provide hands-on technical support.
- 5. **Analyze performance data** for operational efficiency and continuous improvement.

[ 16 Jan 2023 – 8 Mar 2024 ] **Robotics Designer** 

## Photom Technologies Pvt. Ltd

City: Ahmedabad | Country: India

- 1. **Designing** Solar panel **cleaning robots** (Autonomous and Manual).
- 2. **Customizing** Designs as per the customer's request.
- 3. Working with the Electronics and Manufacturing team,

**Guiding** them further to work on the design.

#### **INTERNSHIP**

### [ 12 Sep 2022 – 10 Jan 2023 ] Drone Pilot and Aviation Research Intern | Flyo Eduventures Pvt. Ltd

- 1. Designed and fabricated **medical drone**.
- 2. **Testing** of various drone frames.
- 3. Conducted **research** based on an **aerial survey**

### [18 Jul 2022 – 17 Aug 2022 ] Robotics Instructor and Human resources assistant | Brainlox

- 1. **Coached robotics** to students aged 12-22 years.
- 2. Managed and scheduled lectures as part of the HR team.
- 3. **Answered** students' **questions** and concerns.
- 4. Conducted **onboarding** sessions for **newly joined interns**.

## [ 1 Apr 2019 – 1 May 2020 ] **Digital Marketing Intern | Viral Fission**

1. Conducted Market-based research for brands like Jio Saavn, OnePlus, Myntra,

Vice and Times Network.

- 2. Learned various software like **Adobe Photoshop** and **Adobe Illustrator**.
- 3. Managed the database of these brands and represented it in the form of Gantt charts

and graphs using Tableau and Power Bi

## **EDUCATION AND TRAIN-**ING

## [Sep 2024 - Current] MBA in Technology Management

Tuhh's Northern Institute of Technology Management https://www.nithh.org/

**City:** Hamburg | **Country:** Germany

# [ 18 Aug 2019 – 25 Jun 2023 ] Bachelor Of Technology in Mechanical Engineering

Dwarkadas J. Sanghvi College of engineering https://www.djsce.ac.in/

City: Mumbai | Country: India |

## **EXTRA CURRICULAR**

## [ 20 May 2022 – Current ] Founder and Captain | DJS Astra

- 1. I **formed** and **led** a team of **25 members** from various branches to gain hands-on experience in **combat robotics**.
- 2. Our team, DIS Astra, is interested in combat robot research and development and we compete nationally and internationally.
- 3. We successfully **designed** and **built** three **combat robots** weighing **8 kg**, **15 kg**, and 30 kg.

## [Nov 2021 – Nov 2022] Captain | DJS Phoenix

- 1. I was the Captain of DIS Phoenix, a team of drone enthusiasts, and I mentored a group of 15 people as we designed, built, and competed in autonomous and racing drones in various **national** and **international aerial robotics** events.
- 2. As a result of our collaborative efforts, we successfully built and piloted four drones, and we won prestigious competitions such as COEX, IDRL, and iMAV.

## **PROJECTS**

## [ 10 Jul 2022 – 12 Sep 2022 ] Structural Analysis of a Drone Frame (Solidworks 2021 & Ansys 2020)

- 1. **Analyzed a Drone frame** as a part of the course project for the most appropriate material selection for optimum strength using Ansys 2020.
- 2. Material selection was based on material properties like Tensile Strength, Modulus of Rigidity, Stiffness, and its behavior to loads like Deformation and Stress values.

**Link:** https://cutt.ly/Structural-Analysis-of-a-Drone-Frame

## [ 9 Jan 2021 – 15 Mar 2021 ] **Design of a waterproof drone based on the Lotus concept (Solidworks 2021)**

- 1. The Lotus drone was designed to withstand various harsh climate conditions such as stormy weather, heavy wind, and rain.
- 2. The drone's design makes it suitable for **surveillance** and **rescue missions**.
- 3. Lotus drone **frame** is currently under **patent** process.

**Link:** https://cutt.ly/Lotus---A-waterproof-Drone

#### [ 2 Apr 2020 – 10 Jun 2020 ] **Air ambulance (Solidworks 2020)**

- 1. This project introduces a **drone medical application**.
- 2. Drone-based ideology focuses on bringing aid to victims as rapidly as possible.

- 3. As a result, the victim does not have to wait for an ambulance that may be stalled **in traffic** or in case of **no ambulance** is available.
- 4. It does not require any pilots because it is **Autonomous**.
- 5. The drone is outfitted with a monitor and camera that **connects** the incident site **dir ectly to the doctors**, allowing for on-the-spot First Aid Treatment.

Link: https://cutt.ly/Air-Ambulance-video

[ 11 Mar 2019 – 8 Apr 2019 ] **Vertical Wind turbine (Solidworks 2019 and Blender)** 

- 1. This **portable** vertical wind turbine can be used to **produce power** in **any weather** because of its **mobility**.
- 2. It can be **used** for a **variety of purposes**, including long trips or journeys.
- 3. It weighs less than a kilo, which is incredibly light.

Link: https://cutt.ly/Portable-wind-turbine-video

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

[2023] Swarm Drone Technology

[ 2023 ] Design and Fabrication of bird inspired VTOL UAV

[ 2022 ] Application of Mechatronics in Rail Industry

### **HONOURS AND AWARDS**

[Apr 2023] **2nd position at DJS Nirmiti's Project competition Awarding institution:** Dwarkadas J. Sanghvi college of engineering

> 1. Won **2<sup>nd</sup> rank** among **40 teams** for project titled - Design and Fabrication of biomimetic inspired VTOL UAV

Link: https://cutt.ly/DJS Nirmiti Certificate

[ 23 Apr 2022 ] Grand Finalist of CopterHack'22 Awarding institution: Copter Express

1. Secured 1<sup>st</sup> rank in Asia and 7<sup>th</sup> rank worldwide.

**Links:** https://cutt.ly/COEX-Certificate | https://clover.coex.tech/en/ djs\_phoenix\_ikshana.html

[ 12 Sep 2021 ] Winner of European Rover Challenge Awarding institution: ERC, Kielce University of Technology

> 1. Secured the 1st place internationally after winning four of the five task-based challenges.

Link: https://cutt.ly/ERC-certificate

[Jun 2020] Winner of Engineering Mechanics Quiz Awarding institution: Potti Sriramulu Chalavadi Mallikarjunarao College of Engineering & Technology

1. Scored **92%**, among **100 contestants** from across the nation.

**Link:** <a href="https://cutt.ly/Mechanics-quiz-certificate">https://cutt.ly/Mechanics-quiz-certificate</a>

[ 1 Jun 2020 ] Winner of Electronic's eQuiz competition Awarding institution: SVKM's Shri Bhagubhai Mafatlal Polytechnic

1. I won this quiz with **96%**, edging out **40 competitors** from the state.

Link: <a href="https://cutt.ly/Electronics-e-quiz-certificate">https://cutt.ly/Electronics-e-quiz-certificate</a>

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

**G-Suite Administration Specialization** 

**Link:** https://cutt.ly/Gsuite-specialization-course

MATLAB: Onramp

Link: <a href="https://cutt.ly/Matlab-certificate">https://cutt.ly/Matlab-certificate</a>

# **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Gujarati Other language(s): English